# SALINI PRAKASH

SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER



### **OBJECTIVE**

To give full effort and work for the success of the company where I get placed by utilization of interpersonal skills and creativity. Agile and adaptable with excellent track record, motivated approach and enthusiastic nature

### **ABOUT ME**

A passionate digital marketer who loves to plan projects to present products or services to the right people digitally. And loves to satisfy clients and experience their excitement throughout the entire process. Able to evaluate the results of campaigns and manage the activities and schedules of the creative team. A digital expert marketer who is able to engage the audience while growing the company and create manage the process of selling products or services.

### CONTACT

+916282731824

Krishnamandiram, Temple Raod,Thrikkakara

shaluprakash89@gmail.com

### **EDUCATION**

# Digital Marketing (Diploma)

2021-2022

Graduated Digital Marketing from St.Terasas College, Ernakulam

# **Diploma in Interior designing**

2012-2013

Degree in Interior Designing (Diploma) from New York Art & Design NY, 2013, USA

# Bachelor of Engineering (B.Tech-Civil)

2007-2011

Bachelor of Engineering (B TECH -Civil engineering) from SCMS School of Engineering and technology

### **CERTIFICATION**

**Udemy**- The Compete digital marketing Course-!2 courses inl **LinkedIn**- LinkedIn Marketing Solutions Fundamentals

## **SKILLS**

- Keyword Research: -Research the best keywords using tools like Ahref, Word tracker, Keyword Discovery, and Google
- Keyword Suggestion Tool, Google Insights Search Tool, Good Keyword etc.
- Analytics: Extensive knowledge of website monitoring through page tagging tools such as Google Analytics
- Sales Navigator:-Sales Tool for Prospecting & Insights
- Enhance relationships and strengthen professional relationships

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2022-now

### **Social Media Manager**

- Started as a Social Media manager at Intuisyz Technologies (A Digital Marketing Agency ).
- Worked as a single person to lead their social media (LinkedIn) to increase their followers, engagement, and impressions
- Experience in LinkedIn more
- Managing our online communities to ensure appropriate and respectful engagement Responding to comments on each of our accounts.
- Overseeing customer service provided via social media.
- Work toward enhancing and building the organization's reputation by constantly measuring its effectiveness.
- Develop marketing strategies like calendars and implement marketing plans that increase customer loyalty and retention.
   Understands business to develop marketing programs that increase revenue and attract new customers.
- Developing social media content plans consistent with the company's brand identity.
- Create compelling and results-driven marketing programs to achieve brand and business objectives.
- Help to create content to increase followers

### 1st January 2022- 2022 September

# **Digital Marketing Manager**

- Started as a Digital Marketing Manager at Opsycon Services Private Limited, a DevOps service provider(A startup by a group of experienced software engineers).
- Worked directly as a leader in promoting Opsycon services to promote social media marketing (LinkedIn).
- Update the company page. Create LinkedIn Company Page, Track Job Postings, Evaluate, Manage, Learn What's Trending, Create To Get More Followers Organically
- B2B Marketing Experience- Social Media for Business. Develop marketing strategies and implement marketing plans that increase customer loyalty and retention. Understands business to develop marketing programs that increase revenue and attract new customers.
- Create effective and results-driven marketing programs to achieve brand and business objectives

# 2019-2021 Social Media Manager- freelancer

- Created and managed social media accounts such as
   Facebook and LinkedIn for various clients. Brand Awareness and
   Engagement Traffic to social media accounts increased by 50%.
- It has helped the brand to achieve a strong social media presence by handling daily queries
- Update company pages, developed strategy, managed market.
- Conducted market reaserch to create marketing strategy.
- Responsible for evaluating client websites and developing
   Google My Business to drive more business for the client

#### 2019-2020

### **Assistant manager- Marketing & Administration**

- Worked in a private company as Assistant Manager in administration and marketing.
- Manage and evaluate teams and campaigns.
- Developed and implemented marketing strategies; Analyzed marketing effectiveness and objectives

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Participated in a Webinar by Prof.Raghavan Rao (ICFAI Business school- Bangalore) about the topic Importance of Digital Marketing, which was organized by the Department of commerce in ST.Teresa's College Ernakulam.
- Participated in the workshop conducted by the World Trade Center on April 24, 2021 through Google Meet.
- A webinar on Google Ads & GMB by Mr. ShyamKrishnan P S(Head of Digital Marketing, Kuttukaran Group of Companies) was organized by our Dean Mrs. Raji Zachariah on 26.02.2021.
- Participated in a webinar on March 5, 2021 conducted by the Department of Digital Marketing on e-commerce advertising for shopping campaigns. Mr. Manu Joseph (Digital Marketing Manager- Dubai Economy Department) was the Speaker.

# **DECLARATION**

I hear by declare that all the information atated above is true to best of my knowledge and belief.

#### SALINI PRAKASH